Contact

Cincinnati, OH deloresmincarelli@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/
deloresdataguru (LinkedIn)
public.tableau.com/app/profile/
delores.mincarelli2353 (Portfolio)
rpubs.com/DeloresMincarelli
(Portfolio)

github.com/deloresmincarelli/ BusinessAnalyticsProjects/blob/ master/NurseOptimization.pdf (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Data Science

Python (Programming Language)
Statistical Data Analysis

Languages

Chinese/Mandarin Han Yu Shui Ping Kao Shi Certified Level 2 (Limited Working)

Certifications

Epic Clarity Clinical Reporting - Ambulatory

Epic Clarity Clinical Reporting - Optime

Chinese Mandarin

Epic Clinical Reporting - Stork

Publications

Labor Progression Slower Than the Zhang Standards Is Associated With Worse Maternal and Fetal Outcomes

Reducing Outpatient Opiate
Utilization in the Postpartum Period

Predicting the likelihood that someone has heart disease

Delores Mincarelli

Data Scientist | Critical Thinking | Polished Communicator | Python/ Pyspark | R | SQL | KQL | Alteryx | Azure Synapse | Data Visualization

Louisville, Kentucky, United States

Summary

There is nothing more exciting to me than a new dataset.

For several years I have rolled up my sleeves to help clinicians and managers make better decisions backed by sound data analysis. This required a deep - dive into their business, learning about their problems and concerns, and then being a professional sleuth to find and curate the data to underpin the analytics.

I love using data-for-good.

I'm an end-to-end person .. no need to throw a specification over the wall to me! I work side by side with customers in an iterative and layered approach so we have frequent checks and an evolution of the end result. Sometimes, the end result is a:

- dashboard showing connections between data that has never been linked up before
- analysis answering a question such as: "is this group significantly different from that group"
- predicting an end result
- categorizing observations into logical groupings to bring order and to make large datasets understandable
- bringing a data-science perspective to strategic planning so future decisions complement and provide synergy for machine learning

But one of the most important characteristics I bring is humility and passion for learning; I know how much I don't know. But I'm committed to learning from others and sharing what I know to continually raise the bar for the organization.

Education:

2022 - Master Science: Business Analytics, University of Cincinnati

2017 - Master's Data Analytics Certificate, Xavier University Cincinnati, OH

1985 - Chemical Engineer, Clarkson University, Potsdam, NY

Experience

ClearAsData, LLC
Pricipal and Owner
January 2023 - Present (7 months)
Louisville, KY

Midmark Corporation
Data Scientist
August 2022 - June 2023 (11 months)
Versailles, Ohio, United States

- •Data Engineering: gathering, flattening, cleaning data lake telemetry data into organized tables enabling machine learning.
- •Helped automate process to convert firmware dhall file to digital twin definition language to assess whether incoming telemetry data complies with design specifications.
- •Profiled incoming telemetry data in real time to detect issues and anomalies.

Genetesis Data Analyst May 2022 - August 2022 (4 months) Mason, Ohio, United States

- •Applied statistical methods evaluating variables from two leading magentocardiography publications to determine if publication results were repeatable using Genetesis clinical study data
- •Created methodology for assessing significant magnetocardiography variables to determine healthy and unhealthy ranges.
- •Evaluated certain patient physical characteristics and impact on prediction model accuracy.
- Automated calculation of Sensitivity, Specificity, Accuracy and Confidence Intervals for clinical study results.

TriHealth
6 years 3 months

Data Scientist
April 2019 - January 2022 (2 years 10 months)

Cincinnati

- •Provided significance tests for cardiac surgery department (a) to determine volumes did not support reduction of staff (b) comparing operational efficiencies leading to shared learning between departments.
- •Architected, programmed & delivered seminal work-flow to calculate utilization of anesthesiologists site wide.
- •Provided data & dashboard to influence decision to use median procedure time vs "one size fits all" for high volume procedures in cardiac surgery department.
- •Created views, stored procedures and tables underpinning nurse scheduling optimization project; architected process needed to ETL historical data and do daily refreshes of the data.
- •Prototyped optimization of nurse shift preferences with daily demand,

Lead Business Intelligence Developer November 2015 - March 2019 (3 years 5 months) Cincinnati, OH

- Architected data strategy for Women's Services department to improve quality of data input and for transparency of KPI measures: pushed personalized KPI reports to each provider enabling continued improvement, contributing to highest Leapfrog rating in 2018 for the first time.
- -Found statistical difference in breastfeeding rates based on delivery method, providing focus for improvement work.

Quantified reduction of opioid morphine milligram equivalents (MME) for our inpatient Obstetrics population and provided results for each provider. The calculation of MME's was landmark and provided a standard basis of comparing opioid levels.

Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center Senior Electronic Medical Record Report Writer (EPIC Clarity database) October 2007 - November 2015 (8 years 2 months) Cincinnati, Ohio

University of Cincinnati

Database Programmer, Project Manager 1997 - 2007 (10 years) Cincinnati, OH

The Procter & Gamble Company
Engineer, Department Manager, Supply Chain Logistics
1985 - 1996 (11 years)
Cincinnati, OH

Education

University of Cincinnati

Master of Science - MS, Business Analytics · (September 2019 - April 2022)

Clarkson University
BS, Chemical Engineering · (1981 - 1985)

Xavier University

Master's Certificate, Data Analytics · (2017 - 2017)